Cody Yantis

cyantis@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/cyantis

SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS

IT, instructional, makerspace, supervisory, training, managerial, programming, and metadata experience in public and/or academic libraries

Proficiency in web development (HTML, CSS, and JavaScript), Python programming, e-resource and knowledgebase management; familiarity with SQL, R, Sass, and regular expressions

Experience with Voyager, Sirsi/Dynex, Polaris, and Koha/LibLime ILSes

Proficiency in photo/music/video editing and graphic design software; computer hardware and construction; basic network administration; Microsoft, Libre, and Open Office; academic research databases; Apple, Windows, and Linux OSes and software

Experience with curriculum design; writing, creating, implementing, and interpreting policy; planning and supervising long and short-term projects; documentation and promotional materials

Communicative, collaborative, organizational, analytical, public speaking, conversational Spanish, and problem solving skills.

EXPERIENCE

Denver Public Library April 2013-present

Librarian, Community Technology Center — Denver, CO

- Instruction and curriculum design: computer basics, resume and job skills, computer hardware, privacy and security, web development (WordPress, HTML/CSS, JavaScript), Python programming, open-source software and computing, and Microsoft Office
- Digital media lab programming and instruction: music, video, electronics, and web
 development workshops; 3D printing and design; art and design techniques and
 software; open-source software and computing
- One-on-one technology consultation; collection development; IT help desk; reference; digital imaging services; eMedia support; docent training; outreach

Ruby M. Sisson Memorial Library February 2012-February 2013

Technology Services Librarian — Pagosa Springs, CO

- IT: network administration; PC and software installation and troubleshooting; designed, built, and installed new public computer system; implemented laptop and eReader loan programs; revamped and expanded wireless network; streamlined library website
- Instruction and curriculum design: computer basics, email basics, MS Office series, digital photos, eBooks & eAudio, Skype, blogs & websites basics; hosted twice-weekly tech troubleshooting sessions
- Reference, circulation, shelving, shelf-reading; outreach; tech liaison to the library board

Jones e-global Library June 2011-January 2012

Digital Services Librarian — Centennial, CO

Library website design and implementation; tech support and troubleshooting; electronic content and subscription management; creation and implementation of e-reserve systems; oversight of authentication, link resolvers, and proxies; creation and management of metadata; execution of stats, analytics, and usability initiatives; cataloging; collection development; research, development, and implementation of new trends, initiatives, and technologies

Jones International University / Jones e-global Library December 2010-August 2011 Acting Director of Learning Resources / Library Tech. Coordinator — Centennial, CO

• Interim library director; design and implementation of new library website; library liaison between university administration, students, and faculty; supervision of librarians and employee training; management of interlibrary loan, reference, collection development, electronic databases, and library tech support; assistance with course development

Serials Solutions March 2009-December 2010

Senior Data Acquisition Editor — Seattle, WA

 Knowledgebase management, HTML and regular expression coding, data acquisition and editing, bibliographic and metadata maintenance, and provider/client incident resolution; "new employee excellence" award

The Seattle Public Library September 2008-March 2009

Library Assistant / Directed Fieldwork — Seattle, WA

 Development and implementation of extensive media marketing plan; attendee at numerous city/county refugee and immigrant forums; coordination of programs and community outreach; staffed the ESL/Literacy/World Languages reference desk

Columbia University Libraries October 2007-July 2008

Supervisor, Access Services — The Burke Library, New York, NY

- Supervision and training of fifteen employees in access, circulation, reserves, interlibrary loan, serials, and stacks maintenance; managed the student-employee budget
- Reference; performed tasks for and/or worked closely with special collections, archives, collection development, reference, ReCAP offsite storage, web content management, and cataloging/bibliographic control
- Served on Access Services/Circulation Coordinators, Reserves, Supervisors' Roundtable, and Facilities committees

Fort Vancouver Regional Library District August 2005-July 2007

Library Assistant — Vancouver Mall Community Library, Vancouver, WA

 Reference, circulation, collection development, book mending, program planning, accounting, shelving, and general public library tasks

EDUCATION

Master of Library and Information Science 2009

The Information School — University of Washington, Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Arts in English Literature 2004

University of Puget Sound, Tacoma, WA